#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER III

Summary

I am a dedicated, driven software developer with over 10 years professional experience utilizing a wide variety of languages, including C#, Node.JS, and Java. I am quick and eager to learn, and pick up new languages and technologies effortlessly. I take great pride in my work and am committed to finding the best solution for any given problem. I am seeking the opportunity to work in a like-minded environment, and continue to learn and apply new technologies, skills, and experience, as well as reinforce my existing technical expertise. Highlights

C#, Node.js, Golang, ASP.NET, Ruby, SQL, PHP, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Java Familiar with: Python, AngularJS, Ember, VB.NET, T-SQL, PL/SQL, C/C++ (academic) MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server 2005/2008, Oracle 9i, PostgreSQL, Firebird Platforms: AWS, Docker, Linux (CentOS mostly), OSX, Windows 7, Microsoft Windows XP, Server 2003, Server 2008 Other: Microsoft Visual Studio, Hadoop, NHibernate, WCF, ASP.NET MVC, Wordpress, RESTful services, SOAP/XML, memcached (php), Yii framework (php MVC), git, SVN, AccuRev, ClearCase

Experience

08/2014 to Current

Software Engineer III Walmart i1/4 Mineral Point, WI

- Current team is responsible for taking in candidate data from many different ATS's and importing it to the CareerBuilder platform
- I am currently working on tearing off bits from our current monolithic C#.NET process and moving it into the cloud using a mix of Java, Python, and Node.js, as part of our overall directive to be microservice-focused.
- I receive high praise for being self-directed and having foresight into where we should be going.
- I also serve as a technical mentor for the team.
- On my previous team I helped maintain a legacy applicant tracking system (ATS) written in PHP used by thousands of clients.
- The system is especially difficult to understand and maintain since it uses a custom bloated framework and is littered with French comments and variables
- I was specifically responsible for implementing new features, bug fixes, and converting certain areas into a SOA where possible.
- I was recognized as one of the top performing developers on my team.
- Helped improve our deployment process which was incredibly ancient and difficult to maintain.
- Deploying new code required a developer to spend upwards of several hours pushing out changes and monitoring systems to ensure stability.
- Large changes that required migrations took even longer.
- This legacy system was revamped to push out old versions of the system with greater efficiency which required only a few minutes of developer time.
- In addition, the newest version of the software will utilize a brand new Ruby API for distributed and more robust deployments.

## 08/2012 to 07/2014

Senior Web Developer Motion Recruitment il 4 Stevenson Ranch, CA

- Designed and implemented wardraft.com a daily fantasy sports site.
- Functioned as the primary developer Written using the Yii PHP framework, with a MySQL backend Interfaced with sports XML feeds, written using an event-based system for pushing out live updates via node.js ajax events.
- Tuned and optimized the database (MySQL) for performance as required by tuning queries, indexes, and server side parameters
  Freelanced smaller C# .NET projects, including a utility program to help homeschoolers keep track of homework, grades, and other
  activities.

## 06/2010 to 08/2012

Senior Web Developer Sylmar, CA

- Designed and implemented a large-scale client/server system for performing distributed tasks.
- It was written in C#, using WCF for communication, MySQL for the database, and NHibernate as the ORM.
- Generated thousands of tasks and transactions per day.
- Maintained an ASP.NET/C# application for managing poker leagues.
- I implemented new features as requested by the client, addressed issues, and tackled problems of scale.
- I also orchestrated a migration from SQL Server to MySQL.
- The work on this app has been ongoing through 2015.
- Designed/implemented a "reporting" system using the Yii PHP framework.
- The system consolidates "cost" data from marketing networks such as Adwords and MSN, as well as "revenue" data from 3rd-party systems such as Cake Marketing and Linktrust, and brings it together under one system.
- Designed/implemented a medium-scale affiliate tracking and marketing system for a niche market.
- System was designed in ASP.NET, and is being converted to use ASP.NET MVC.
- Developed custom plugins and themes for Wordpress, including a large custom-designed flexible project management plugin allowing users
  to configure their own "templates" and work items.
- It also included an integrated time management system and reporting tool allowing contractors to accurately bill for time and projects worked.
- Administered several web servers, including backup/restore of sites and general configuration; custom configuration of PHP, Apache, IIS, SQL Server, and MySQL Experience developing and maintaining existing websites and creating new custom-coded sites from scratch Worked directly with clients in analyzing needs and system requirements Tuned and optimized the databases (MySQL and SQL Server) for

performance as required by tuning queries, indexes, and server side parameters.

# 06/2004 to 06/2010

Analyst/Research Analyst Southwest Research Institute il/4 City, STATE

- Full time software development working in both Java and C# Gather requirements, design, implement, and maintain multiple components in multi-tiered applications, utilizing a variety of technologies and languages including C# and java.
- Knowledge of SQL and different database products, including SQL Server, MySQL, and Oracle.
- Generated reports using Oracle PL/SQL stored procedures handling thousands of records Served as the de-facto DBA for 1 year supporting the project's SQL Server and legacy Oracle databases.
- Handled upgrade scripts, performance analysis and optimization, and disaster recovery scenarios when required.
- Member of the Configuration Management (CM) team responsible for builds and stream management.
- Task Lead responsible for 5 team members.
- Provide technical and functional support and guidance.

### Education

Spring 2004

B.S: Computer Science Trinity University il/4 City, State Computer Science

December 2005

Knowledge of Visual C#, C++, Java, MPI, computer design, networking, graphics, parallel processing, software lifecycle, simulation and modeling, symbolic logic, SQL and databases, and practical applications Computer maintenance and some repair skills; building computers Economics Minor Knowledge of both Micro and Macroeconomics Advanced economic theory, emphasis on environmental and urban applications Certifications Oracle Certified Associate, Oracle 9i DBA Crystal Reports 9.0 Intro+Advanced Skills

VB.NET, C#.NET, C#.NET, ASP.NET, academic, ajax, Apache, API, backup, building computers, C, Visual C, C++, ClearCase, client/server, com, Computer maintenance, Configuration Management, Crystal Reports 9.0, CSS, client, clients, DBA, databases, Database, disaster recovery, Economics, XML, features, French, functional, graphics, HTML, PHP, IIS, Java, Javascript, Linux, logic, managing, marketing, market, mentor, C#, Windows 7, Microsoft Windows XP, migration, modeling, MSN, MVC, MySQL, networking, networks, optimization, Oracle 9, Oracle, developer, Oracle PL/SQL, PL/SQL, performance analysis, PostgreSQL, project management, Python, reporting, scripts, simulation, SOAP, software development, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, SQL Server, time management, T-SQL, upgrade, Microsoft Visual Studio, web servers, websites, Written